adjustable dumbbells are some of the
best pieces of equipment you can add to
your home gym they're Compact and
they're going to save you money as
opposed to purchasing a full set of
traditional dumbbells but you know a
problem with a lot of them is that they
feature a ton of plastic now that's not
the case with the snowed adjustable
dumbbells these beasts are made almost
entirely of iron so they're super
durable and they range from 10 to 80
pounds these might be my new favorite
adjustable dumbbells on the market so
I'm really excited for this review today
let's get right to it oh
what's up y'all it's Jake back in the
barbing garage gym and for today's video
I've got a pair of snowed adjustable
dumbbells that I'm going to be breaking
down for y'all in this video today I'm
going to tell you everything you need to
know about these adjustable dumbbells
we're going to talk about the price
we're going to talk about some of the
features we're gonna go over some of my
pros and cons but most importantly you
know who should or maybe should not
purchase these now before I do that
we've reviewed a ton of adjustable
dumbbells on barbin.com and we went
ahead and made a best list as well so if
you want to check that out all you got
to do is search barvin best adjustable
dumbbells that list is going to pull
right up for you and you can find out
for yourself which ones we like the best
so as I mentioned these might be my new
favorite adjustable dumbbells on the
market so there's obviously going to be
a whole lot to like about them I think
the first thing we need to talk about is
how easy it is to adjust the weight you
just twist this dial right here and
you're able to fly through all the
weight increments which is 10 to 80
pounds it's going to replace 16 pairs of
dumbbells which is going to create a lot
more floor space but also you know 80
pounds is pretty heavy the most
adjustable dumbbells cap out around 50
to 55 pounds so you need more than that
which a lot of people do that's really
nice these are going to be a solid you
know choice for you to choose from these
are made almost entirely of metal
actually 90 of iron other than that
adjustment mechanism which is of course
plastic it's kind of the case with every
single adjustable dumbbell out there the
knurling here is also really nice and
this handle right here is actually
thicker than most adjustable dumbbells
as well so honestly it kind of feels as
if you're using a traditional dumbbell
which is something that I just really
love now those nice things being said
there are a few things you might run
into you're not be too crazy about and
first thing is the money right so
because of you know the minimal plastic
used and how structurally sound these
are these are going to cost you around
800 shipping is free which is nice it's
gonna take around four to five weeks to
get them though so definitely keep that
in mind but 800 price tag which is you
know bound to increase with some add-ons
and one of them that I think is
absolutely worth it is the magnetic
weights they're gonna cost you about 40
bucks but the reason I say it's worth it
because these only adjust in 10 pound
increments and that's not something I
personally look for with with you know
dumbbells adjustable dumbbells because
you know you're doing a lot of isolation
movements right you know you're doing
your lateral raises front raises you
know overhead tricep extensions you're
not necessarily looking to jump in 10
pound increments with those lifts so
getting those magnetic weights is worth
it to me but it is going to add on to
your total
foreign
adjustable dumbbells from snowed are
going to run you right around 800 bucks
but tack on those magnetic weights and
the optional stand that's going to bump
you up to around eleven hundred dollars
that's a lot of money that's a lot of
money for adjustable dumbbells but in my
opinion they certainly fit the bill you
know they are almost entirely made of
metal the knurling right here on this
handle is really sweet to me it's really
easy for you to adjust the weight and
they get as heavy as 80 pounds which is
a really good thing right there and
actually if you get those magnetic
weights it's actually going to bump up
you know heavier than that which is
pretty cool too now if you don't need 80
pounds or you know maybe 800 bucks is
just too much but you kind of want this
build right here they do have you know a
pair of 50 pound adjustable dumbbells
and those are going to run you around
600.
foreign
[Music]
so once again these dumbbells are pretty
much entirely made of iron even the the
cradles right here which are cast iron
the plates are cast iron the handles
right here are Chrome plated iron on the
inside is an aluminum rod that whenever
you which this adjustment mechanism is
plastic but whenever you adjust it that
aluminum rod is going to extend and
that's how you're selecting these plates
right here so when they're in the
cradles they measure about 19 and a half
inches long about seven and a half
inches wide they're roughly like eight
inches tall so you can slide these under
your bed which is a really nice thing
you know super compact I really like
these handles right here as well you
know as I mentioned they are you know
Chrome plated so it's going to help with
some Rust and corrosion and everything
but they're about 36 millimeters in
diameter about 1.4 inches and that's
really nice you know it's pretty thick
it's going to fill up your palms and the
knurling right here is really nice too
you know it's it's not passive it's not
you know abrasive no dumbbells really
are right but they give you a really
solid grip and I personally like how
it's you know straight neural all the
way across it's end to end right here
it's not an ergonomically shaped handle
so ergonomic handles they're thicker in
the middle and they're on the ends I
personally don't like that so I think
that you know the fact that snow just
stuck with that straight across handle
right here is a really cool thing
thank you
all right so I want to highlight you
know some of the build and features with
these adjustable dumbbells and remember
these are pretty much all made of iron
including these cast iron cradles right
here everything except for the actual
adjustment mechanism but actually come
here I want to show you guys up close
really quick all right so super easy to
adjust the the weight right here all you
do is Twist this dial and then boom
you're flying through and you're 80
pounds already now that's really cool
just remember you know it's all 10 pound
increments you know you're not going to
have any two and a half or five pound
unless you get those magnetic weights so
if you get those you get eight of them
each one is 1.25 pounds you literally
just stack them on the ends right here
of the actual dumbbell head and that's
how you know you get those extra
increments which is really cool so the
handle right here 36 millimeters which
is right around 1.4 inches in diameter
it's really nice it's going to fill up
your palms thicker than the majority of
adjustable dumbbells out there so you
can probably even work on your grip
strength a little bit now even the inner
Rod right here is aluminum so even that
is metal the actual handle right here is
iron that's coated in Chrome which is
pretty cool and now they don't have a
flat bottom they're rounded on the
bottom so they're not going to be ideal
for doing any push-ups or anything like
that but these are super durable and
they're tested and rated to drop from 32
inches without breaking and that's even
with the 10 pound increment right here
you know it's super sturdy feels really
solid now there's still a little bit of
a wobble you can hear the plate
did you hear that a little bit that's
okay you know I mean it's bound to
happen it's there's only no way to avoid
that you know it's just the overall
design in general nothing to worry about
at all it doesn't affect me I don't
think it'll affect you either these
measure in the Cradle about 19 and a
half inches long about seven and a half
inches wide and about eight inches tall
or so so you can definitely you know
slide these under your bed if you need
to put them in a closet there's a lot of
you know possibilities in terms of
storage and it's just going to create a
whole lot of more floor space you know
within your home gym and everything
which is really cool so when we talk
about you know who these dumbbells are
right for you got to talk about the
obvious you know if you want the utility
that a full set of dumbbells provides
you don't have the space for it
adjustable dumbbells in general are
going to be the way to go but you know
these specifically are really tailored
to anybody who needs you know 80 pounds
of weight if you get those magnetic
weights you know up to 85 for each one
80 to 85 pounds of weight and you know
anybody who just wants some you know
long lasting which you kind of should
long lasting adjustable dumbbells you're
going to really like this cast iron
build but that being said because of
that you know durable build and
everything they're really expensive so
they're going to cost you anywhere from
800 to 1100 so if that's not within your
wheelhouse I suggest going after you
know some cheaper options that are out
there and then not everybody needs 80
pounds of weight if you don't remember
you know most of them are going to run
around 50 to 55 pounds so you can find
plenty of other options remember snow
does have a pair of 50 pound adjustable
dumbbells still going to cost you around
600 bucks and that's you know due to you
know that cast iron build so just kind
of keep those things in mind
[Music]
that's a wrap on today's review over the
snowed adjustable dumbbells yes I know
they're expensive but these are my
personal favorites right now super easy
to adjust the weight they're really
heavy you know 80 pounds once I get
those magnetic weights they're going to
be 85 pounds a piece and it's going to
you know sprinkle in some one and a half
and two two and a half pound increments
and everything and then plus you know
the durable build means they're going to
last a super long time thanks for
watching y'all hope this video is really
helpful and I was able to break down
these in full for you guys as always
stay posted for my next video but for
now head over to barbin.com because we
have a full written review about these
adjustable dumbbells all you gotta do is
search bar Bend snowed adjustable
dumbbell review our article is going to
pull up you can go over everything we
talked about here today I'll catch y'all
next time
foreign
[Music]